say something say something it's the
21st century's golden rule because we're
told danger lurks around every corner
from kidnap immigrants vaccines but in
general doesn't fear at least help to
keep us safe Barry glass there is a
sociologist who wrote a book called the
culture of fear why Americans are afraid
of the wrong things and hosts a podcast
called fear not
so after patting him down thoroughly for
weapons I asked him what's wrong with
being afraid of things it's not good for
your health
it's not good for the world it's not
good for your country it's bad in every
possible way almost give me a list of a
few things that we're afraid of that we
shouldn't be afraid of terrorism in the
US but what do you mean we say we saw it
happen 9/11 we saw much more likely to
get killed or hurt in all kinds of other
ways it should be more afraid of your
slippery bathtub rickety furniture in
your house they're much more likely to
kill you
so the furniture being put together by
Muslim fundamentalists since we've been
trying to get it start carrying it
there's lots of things the US should
fear more than terrorism lawn mowers
mowed am way more Americans each year
than Islam driving my seagulls getting
struck but if logic tells us we should
be less worried about Isis and shoe
bombers why do we hear so much about
them I mean the reason is because there
all sorts of people making a lot of
careers officers cable TV news social
media and the crazy thing about this is
this is about the safest time and the
safest place in the world in the US
right now what else we should not be
afraid of almost anything that Donald
Trump tells us to be afraid of but do
you think he believes any of the things
that he says I know one thing he
certainly believes it'll get him votes
Donald Trump's formulas this right get
you afraid of something
American carnage their rapists and say
that he can fix it this is so easy to
fix and oftentimes it only he can fix it
I alone
can fix it that's a great thing to do
when crime rates are going down right
because guess what you can say you fixed
it now sure it's easy to call Trump out
but he didn't invent all this and it's a
vicious cycle with each side feeding off
each other what's a more Democrat sort
of fear-mongering think they try to get
you to write checks by sending you these
scary pictures Donald Trump
that's fear mongering they left feeling
or a lot more with the foods they get
Whole Foods on you
there's tons of fear-mongering about
food from the left and from liberals
absolutely some trans fats coming to get
you so politicians do it for power the
media does it for writings and then
there are the people doing it purely for
money the security industry which is
huge it's constantly coming up with new
products now you can monitor your home
watch your kids from every angle on your
watch what that does is make you more
fearful yeah and then when they get to
18 you know I say your daughter being
fingered on the couch or anything
in fact when this beard thing really
takes hold it can have some pretty dire
consequences can you die from fear oh
yeah vaccines Gear's
great example people stop vaccinating
kids and people die yeah you're so
obsessed with the thing you're fearful
about that you're not paying attention
the way should be what's the easy fix
what do we do I mean you have to learn
who's selling you the fears why are they
doing it what are they getting out of it
and once you recognize those you can
turn it out right now at the start of
the presidential election there's
probably nothing more important than
learning to be skeptical of anyone who
stands to gain from making us all scared
shitless but since Barry here is the
expert I need him to roll on a few
things once and for all
okay I'm gonna rattle off some things
you tell me I should be fearful of these
groups Mexicans know next to be storming
the border Mexican
Jonah's not aliens they can be and I can
be sneaky with typing part I wasn't even
thinking about that when I started my
diet it's Perry
[Music]